webmasterformat.com 2016-03-06

# WebmasterFormat - Privacy Policy

Welcome to WebmasterFormat.com

The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this website - webmasterformat.com. If you require any more information or have any questions concerning privacy while visiting this website, please feel free to contact us by visiting this url: <http://webmasterformat.com/contact>.

## Log Files

Like many other Web sites, webmasterformat.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

## Cookies

Cookies are assigned to visitors in order to save their preferences and analyze referrer data. Accessing this website is not dependent on accepting cookies and all major browsers allow you to disable cookies if you wish. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options.

## Third Party Cookies

Cookies that collect anonymous traffic data are used on this website as a result of usage of third party analytics software – Google Analytics. This data is primarily used to optimize this website for its visitors. This data does not include any personally identifiable information. Google Analytics tracks visitors who have Javascript enabled. If you wish to disable Javascript, you may do so through your individual browser options.

### DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on webmasterformat.com.  
Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to webmasterformat.com and other sites on the Internet.  
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:  

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on webmasterformat.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

webmasterformat.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. webmasterformat.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

## Links

webmasterformat.com website frequently link to other websites and is not responsible for the content or business practices of these websites. When you leave this websites you’re encouraged to read the destination site’s privacy policy. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by webmasterformat.com.

## Email Addresses

When registering for an account or signing up for a newsletter, you are required to provide your email address. Your email will never be shared with any third party and will be removed at your request which can be sent via this [contact form](http://webmasterformat.com/contact).

## ClickTale Tracking

This site uses ClickTale web analytics service. ClickTale may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as any text you type in this website. ClickTale does not collect passwords or any personally identifiable information that you do not voluntarily enter in this website. ClickTale does not track your browsing habits across web sites which do not use ClickTale services. For more information see [Privacy Policy for Information Collected by the ClickTale Web Analytics Service](http://www.clicktale.com/privacy_service.aspx). We are using the information collected by ClickTale service to better understand our visitors so we could provide them with better service.  
You can choose to disable the Service at <http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html>.

## Notification of Changes

Any changes to this privacy policy will be posted here.
